ALI ZAHID

CONTACT

Address: London UB3 4AS Phone: 07944588500

Email: alizahid98@live.co.uk LinkedIn: https://rb.gy/dgywr9

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

Website: https://alizahid117.github.io./

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- SQL
- Python
- Databases
- Swift
- SwiftUI
- Git
- GitHub
- Problem-solving
- Leadership and management skills
- Business administration and commercial awareness
- Revenue growth and brand management

EDUCATION

A-Levels: Biology, History, 09/2015 – 07/2017

Harlington School - London

- Biology C
- History C

GCSEs, 09/2012 - 07/2014 Harlington School - London

- 1 A (Biology A)
- 8 B's (Math B, English B, Physics B, Chemistry B)

MY GITHUB REPOSITORIES

• https://github.com/AliZahid117?tab=repositories

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am enthusiastic and passionate about software development. I recently completed an intense and extensive government-funded software development boot camp, which provided me with valuable web and software development skills. I have been building various projects in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, and Swift which I have linked on this CV to my GitHub repositories, and my website is linked on this CV. From making my first computer at the age of eight to learning how to code I have always been fascinated by computers and development. I have proven skills in project management from seven years managing a property business, I also have international experience working in America and Belgium.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT HISTORY

12- week Software Development Boot camp, 02/04/2024 – 21/06/2024

Just IT Ltd, London

- Intense 12-week government-funded boot camp, covering core web and software development skills and concepts.
- The course curriculum covered: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Database design, SQL, and software development methodologies.
- As part of my course, I completed five projects to showcase my software development skills, which are linked on my portfolio website.
- This boot camp helped me hone and fine-tune my development skills.

Software Development certificates

- Codecademy CSS certificate
- Codecademy HTML certificate
- Codecademy Python, Al and chatbot certificate

Projects - All my projects are linked on my GitHub:

Python generative Al project:

I created a generative AI chat box to answer questions for users visiting my website. This project showcases my skills in Python and AI design.

• Film finder:

This project highlights my skills with front-end technologies with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the ability to utilise APIs, to increase functionality for the user.

HOBBIES

- Guitar
- Programming
- Swimming

WORK HISTORY

Manager, 08/2017 to 06/2024

Z Properties - London

- Seven years managing a family property portfolio of five houses.
- Responsibilities as manager included: preparing the yearly tax return, hiring, and managing builders for repairs and refurbishments on the houses, acquiring new and maintaining existing tenants, and dealing with tenant queries.
- I built positive relationships with my tenants to maintain the high standards of the company brand.
- Identified, planned, and implemented new real estate projects.
- Carried out refurbishments on the houses to increase profits by over 50% from the rent and saved the business money by building two kitchens by myself.

Camp counsellor/ Lifeguard, 06/2019 to 08/2019 Camp America/ Kennolyn Camps - Soquel California

- International experience working as a camp counsellor in America through Camp America.
- My roles were: Counsellor, lifeguard, guitar instructor, and basketball coach.
- Worked as a professionally qualified RLSS UK lifeguard.
- Participated in meetings to coordinate with other staff on the camper's progress, issues, and goal achievements.
- Implemented camp activities fostering physical, social, and emotional growth.

Night shop assistant, 05/2022 to 09/2022 Nachtwinkel Lochristi Lo-Bravo - Lochristi, Belgium

- International experience working in Belgium dealing with customers and fostering positive customer relationships.
- Prepared invoices for customers with large and special orders.